Guide to the Norman Dorsen Papers TAM.251
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series V: Arthur Garfield Hays Civil Liberties Program
  - Convocation - State Commission on Human Rights, Mar 1964-Nov 1964 (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - Future Projects, 1959-1962 (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - History and reports, 1962-1967 (Box 28, Folder 16)
  - Legal Services - Abortion - Hall, et al. civil action 3090, 1970 (Box 28, Folder 17)
  - Legal Services - Abortion - Hall, et al. civil action 4284, 1969 (Box 28, Folder 18)
  - Legal Services - Abortion - Vuitch, 1970-1985 (Box 28, Folder 19)
  - Legal Services - ACLU - "Clear and Present Danger", 1966-1967 (Box 28, Folder 20)
  - Legal Services - ACLU - Abortion case, 1968-1969 (Box 28, Folder 21)
  - Legal Services - ACLU - Alabama Lawyer article, 1962-1963 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Legal Services - ACLU - Apodaca, 1972 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Legal Services - ACLU - Barnett Case, 1963-1964 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Legal Services - ACLU - Brandenberg, 1968-1969 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Legal Services - ACLU - Conscription and Civil Liberties, 1965-1966 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Legal Services - ACLU - Estes v. Texas, 1964-1965 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Legal Services - ACLU - Federal Communications Commission Recommendations, 1966-1967 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Legal Services - ACLU - Free press vs. fair trial, 1964-1966 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Legal Services - ACLU - George O'Neil, 1961-1962 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Legal Services - ACLU - Gideon v. Cochran and Gideon v. Wainwright, 1962-1963 (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Legal Services - ACLU - Gojack, Feb 1966 (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Legal Services - ACLU - Gotthilf Case, 1963-1964 (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Legal Services - ACLU - House Un-American Activities Committee, 1963-1964 (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - Legal Services - ACLU - International - Puerto Rican Elections, 1961-1962 (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - Legal Services - ACLU - International - Security for Good Behavior, 1961-1962 (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - Legal Services - ACLU - Labine v. Vincent, 1970-1971 (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - Legal Services - ACLU - Loyalty oaths, 1966-1967 (Box 29, Folder 17)
  - Legal Services - ACLU - Network ban on Communist Party speakers, 1963-1964 (Box 29, Folder 18)
  - Legal Services - ACLU - Noyd case, 1966-1967 (Box 29, Folder 19)
  - Legal Services - ACLU - Overseas Weekly, 1961-1962 (Box 29, Folder 20)
  - Legal Services - ACLU - Perez and Gomez, 1970-1973 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Legal Services - ACLU - PFC Owen, 1961-1962 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Legal Services - ACLU - Phillips v. Martin Marietta, 1969-1971 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Legal Services - ACLU - Reapportionment Amendment, 1965 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Legal Services - ACLU - Reid v. Reid, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Legal Services - ACLU - Roger Baldwin Foundation of the ACLU - Farm labor case, 1967 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Legal Services - ACLU - Rosengart, 1971 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Legal Services - ACLU - See v. Seattle, 1966-1967 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Legal Services - ACLU - Smith Case, 1963-1964 (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Legal Services - ACLU - Soblen Case, 1962-1963 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Legal Services - ACLU - Staats v. ACLU, 1973-1974 (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Legal Services - ACLU - U.S. v. Mississippi, 1963-1964 (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Legal Services - ACLU - United States v. Marchetti, 1972 (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - Legal Services - ACLU - Wainwright v. New Orleans, 1967-1968 (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - Legal Services - ACLU - Williams Case, 1969-1970 (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - Legal Services - ACLU of Southern California - Prohibitions of Federal Rights of Felons, 1965 (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - Legal Services - ACLU of Southern California - Teachers' rights not to inform, 1962-1963 (Box 30, Folder 17)
  - Legal Services - ACLU of Southern California - Validity of Oath Required of Users of Public Facilities for Public Meetings, 1963-1964 (Box 30, Folder 18)
  - Legal Services - ACLU of Southern California- Communist Party speakers at the University of California, 1961-1962 (Box 30, Folder 19)
  - Legal Services - ACLU of Washington - Judicial Review of Education Act, 1964-1965 (Box 30, Folder 20)
  - Legal Services - American Association of University Professors - Loyalty oaths, 1964-1965 (Box 30, Folder 21)
  - Legal Services - American Association of University Professors - Loyalty oaths, 1964-1965 (Box 30, Folder 22)
  - Legal Services - American Jewish Committee - Antitrust laws and racial discrimination, 1961-1962 (Box 30, Folder 23)
  - Legal Services - American Jewish Committee - Application of Civil Rights Act to Individuals in D.C., 1962-1963 (Box 30, Folder 24)
  - Legal Services - American Jewish Committee - Authority of Tulsa Enact Ordinance, 1962-1963 (Box 30, Folder 25)
  - Legal Services - American Jewish Committee - Discrimination in "private" clubs, 1962-1963 (Box 30, Folder 26)
  - Legal Services - American Jewish Congress - Boycott of Standard Oil, 1962-1963 (Box 30, Folder 27)
  - Legal Services - American Jewish Congress - De facto school segregation, 1966-1967 (Box 30, Folder 28)
  - Legal Services - American Jewish Congress - Enjoining Recordation of Restrictive Covenants, 1962-1963 (Box 30, Folder 29)
  - Legal Services - American Jewish Congress - Medicare Freedom of Choice, 1966 (Box 30, Folder 30)
  - Legal Services - American Jewish Congress - Mulkey v. Reitman, 1967 (Box 30, Folder 31)
  - Legal Services - American Jewish Congress - Supreme Court Summary, 1963 (Box 30, Folder 32)
  - Legal Services - American Jewish Congress - Ultra vires Contributions, 1964 (Box 30, Folder 33)
  - Legal Services - Atlee v. Antiwar, 1972 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Legal Services - Briguglio Case, 1969 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Legal Services - Brunnenkant civil action, 1972 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Legal Services - Center on Corporate Responsibility, 1973-1974 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Legal Services - Colasurdo case, 1970 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Legal Services - Congress of Racial Equality (CORE) - Alabama jurisdiction over CORE, 1962-1963 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Legal Services - CORE - Arrest on suspicion, 1962-1963 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Legal Services - CORE - Callender Case, 1966 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Legal Services - CORE - Los Angeles Transportation, 1966 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Legal Services - CORE - Mississippi bail recovery, 1963-1964 (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Legal Services - CORE - Mississippi sit-in case, 1962-1963 (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Legal Services - CORE - New Jersey "live-ins", 1962-1963 (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Legal Services - CORE - Oklahoma miscegenation statute, 1965 (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - Legal Services - CORE - Tax-free bonds for segregated schools, 1963-1964 (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - Legal Services - CORE - Validity of California Trust, 1961-1962 (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - Legal Services - De Funis Case, 1972-1974 (Box 31, Folder 16)
  - Legal Services - Emergency Civil Liberties Committee (ECLC) - Danville conspiracy, 1963-1964 (Box 31, Folder 17)
  - Legal Services - ECLC - Green v. Board of Elections, 1967-1968 (Box 31, Folder 18)
  - Legal Services - ECLC - Indiana students, 1963-1964 (Box 31, Folder 19)
  - Legal Services - ECLC - Julian Bond case, 1966-1967 (Box 31, Folder 20)
  - Legal Services - ECLC - Kentucky miners, 1963-1964 (Box 31, Folder 21)
  - Legal Services - ECLC - Koch case, 1963-1964 (Box 31, Folder 22)
  - Legal Services - ECLC - Lamont case, 1963-1964 (Box 31, Folder 23)
  - Legal Services - ECLC - Lamont case, 1964-1965 (Box 31, Folder 24)
  - Legal Services - ECLC - Right of aliens to leave the U.S., 1962-1963 (Box 31, Folder 25)
  - Legal Services - ECLC - Zemel v. Rusk, 1964-1965 (Box 31, Folder 26)
  - Legal Services - Finance of minority parties, 1967 (Box 31, Folder 27)
  - Legal Services - Flast v. Gardner, 1967-1970 (Box 31, Folder 28)
  - Legal Services - George Sing Louie (Gen. Decker), 1971 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Legal Services - Hensley Case, 1967 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Legal Services - Hodgson et al v. Randall (James Madison), Nov 1970 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Legal Services - In Re Cager, 1968 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Legal Services - International League for the Rights of Man - Rights of arrested persons, 1962-1963 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Legal Services - Korin - Juvenile Case (Fletcher), 1967-1969 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Legal Services - Korin - Juvenile Case (Fletcher), 1968-1969 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Legal Services - Kraus Case, 1966-1970 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Legal Services - Kunstler Contempt case, 1973-1974 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Legal Services - Legal Services Corporation, 1977-1978 (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Legal Services - Levy v. Louisiana, 1960-1971 (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Legal Services - Levy v. Louisiana, 1966-1967 (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - Legal Services - Levy v. Louisiana, 1967 (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - Legal Services - Levy v. Louisiana, 1967-1968 (Box 32, Folder 14)
  - Legal Services - Levy v. Louisiana, 1968 (Box 32, Folder 15)
  - Legal Services - Levy v. Louisiana, 1968 (Box 32, Folder 16)
  - Legal Services - Levy v. Louisiana - ACLU, 1960-1967 (Box 32, Folder 17)
  - Legal Services - Master list of case files, 1961-1981 (Box 32, Folder 18)
  - Legal Services - Mink v. Environmental, 1971-1973 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Legal Services - Miscellaneous, 1961-1965 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Legal Services - Miscellaneous, 1966-1967 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Legal Services - Miscellaneous, 1967-1968 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Legal Services - Miscellaneous, 1967-1968 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Legal Services - Miscellaneous, 1967-1968 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Legal Services - Miscellaneous, 1970 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Legal Services - Miscellaneous, 1971-1972 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Legal Services - Miscellaneous, 1973-1974 (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Legal Services - Miscellaneous, 1973-1974 (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Legal Services - Miscellaneous, 1973-1976 (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - Legal Services - Miscellaneous, 1975-1976 (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - Legal Services - Morris v. Richardson, 1972 (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - Legal Services - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (NAACP) - Barksdale petition, 1965 (Box 33, Folder 14)
  - Legal Services - NAACP - Equal Employment Opportunity Commission - Seniority Conference, Jun 1966 (Box 33, Folder 15)
  - Legal Services - NAACP - Legal Defense Fund - Southern Christian Leadership Conference and Student Non-Violent Coordinating Committee, 1966 (Box 33, Folder 16)
  - Legal Services - NAACP - Legal Defense Fund - Wanwatosa Ordinance, 1967 (Box 33, Folder 17)
  - Legal Services - NAACP - Manual for demonstrators, 1963-1964 (Box 33, Folder 18)
  - Legal Services - NAACP - Medical discrimination, 1961-1962 (Box 33, Folder 19)
  - Legal Services - New York Civil Liberties Union (NYCLU) - Condon - Wadlin Act, 1963-1964 (Box 33, Folder 20)
  - Legal Services - NYCLU - Extradition, 1966 (Box 33, Folder 21)
  - Legal Services - NYCLU - Screening of prison mail, 1965-1966 (Box 33, Folder 22)
  - Legal Services - NYCLU - Weiss Bill, 1964-1965 (Box 33, Folder 23)
  - Legal Services - NYCLU -Wood Case, 1962-1968 (Box 33, Folder 24)
  - Legal Services - Pittsburgh press case, 1972-1973 (Box 33, Folder 25)
  - Legal Services - Planned Parenthood - Abortion, 1966 (Box 33, Folder 26)
  - Legal Services - Residence Case, 1967-1968 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Legal Services - Residence Case, 1967-1968 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Legal Services - Residence Case, 1967-1968 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Legal Services - Roe v. Norton, 1973-1974 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Legal Services - Senator Javits - Supreme Court study, 1962-1963 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Legal Services - Senator Kennedy - Firearms control, 1965 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Legal Services - Senator Kennedy - Statute on physical interference with rights, 1965 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Legal Services - Specht v. Patterson, 1965-1967 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Legal Services - Spock/Coffin Case, 1968-1970 (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Legal Services - Sykes Case, 1968-1969 (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Legal Services - Trimble v. Gordon, 1976 (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - Legal Services - U.S. v. Coleman, 1964-1965 (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - Legal Services - U.S. v. Ellsberg, 1972-1973 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Legal Services - U.S. v. Ellsberg, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Legal Services - U.S. v. Nixon, 1974 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Legal Services - U.S. v. Nixon - Briefs, 1973 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Legal Services - U.S.A. v. Committee for Impeachment, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Legal Services - United Church - military chaplain, 1971 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Legal Services - United Nations - Implementation of human rights, 1962-1963 (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Legal Services - United States Civil Rights Commission, 1962-1964 (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Legal Services - United States Civil Rights Commission - Representation of unpopular defendants, 1961-1962 (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - Legal Services - Varaga School Case, 1969 (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - Legal Services - Varaga v. Criminal Court, 1969 (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - Legal Services - Weber v. Aetna Casualty, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 12)
  - National Defender Project, 1968-1972 (Box 35, Folder 13)
  - National Defender Project, 1966-1967 (Box 35, Folder 14)
  - Project on Social Welfare Law (PSWL) - Correspondence, Jan 1967 (Box 35, Folder 15)
  - PSWL - Correspondence, Feb 1967 (Box 35, Folder 16)
  - PSWL - Correspondence, Mar 1967 (Box 35, Folder 17)
  - PSWL - Correspondence, Apr 1967 (Box 35, Folder 18)
  - PSWL - Correspondence, May 1967 (Box 35, Folder 19)
  - PSWL - Correspondence, Jun 1967 (Box 35, Folder 20)
  - PSWL - Correspondence, Jul 1967 (Box 35, Folder 21)
  - PSWL - Correspondence, Aug 1967 (Box 35, Folder 22)
  - PSWL - Correspondence, Sep 1967 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - PSWL - Correspondence, Oct 1967 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - PSWL - Correspondence, Nov 1967 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - PSWL - Correspondence, Dec 1967 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - PSWL - Correspondence, Jan 1968 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - PSWL - Correspondence, Feb 1968 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - PSWL - Correspondence, Mar 1968 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - PSWL - Correspondence, Apr 1968 (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - PSWL - Correspondence, May 1968 (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - PSWL - Correspondence, Jun 1968 (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - PSWL - Correspondence, Jul 1968 (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - PSWL - Correspondence, Aug 1968 (Box 36, Folder 12)
  - PSWL - Correspondence, Sep 1968 (Box 36, Folder 13)
  - PSWL - Correspondence, Oct 1968 (Box 36, Folder 14)
  - PSWL - Correspondence, Nov 1968 (Box 36, Folder 15)
  - PSWL - Correspondence, Dec 1968 (Box 36, Folder 16)
  - PSWL - Correspondence, Jan 1969 (Box 36, Folder 17)
  - PSWL - Correspondence, Feb 1969 (Box 36, Folder 18)
  - PSWL - Correspondence, Mar 1969 (Box 36, Folder 19)
  - PSWL - Correspondence, Apr 1969 (Box 36, Folder 20)
  - PSWL - Correspondence, May 1969 (Box 36, Folder 21)
  - PSWL - Correspondence, Jun 1969 (Box 36, Folder 22)
  - PSWL - Field Foundation Application, 1963-1967 (Box 36, Folder 23)
  - PSWL - Field Foundation Proposal, 1966 (Box 36, Folder 24)
  - PSWL - Field Welfare Project, 1964-1965 (Box 36, Folder 25)
  - PSWL - Field Welfare Project, 1965-1966 (Box 36, Folder 26)
  - PSWL - Field Welfare Project, 1966 (Box 36, Folder 27)
  - PSWL - Field Welfare Project - Finances, 1965-1967 (Box 36, Folder 28)
  - PSWL - Field Welfare Project - Personnel, 1965-1967 (Box 36, Folder 29)
  - PSWL - Finances, 1968-1969 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - PSWL - Miscellaneous, 1967-1968 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - PSWL - Miscellaneous, 1968-1969 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - PSWL - Office of Economic Opportunity, 1966-1968 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - PSWL - Office of Economic Opportunity, 1967-1968 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - PSWL - Personnel, 1968-1969 (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - PSWL - Testimony, 1967 (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - PSWL - Wind-up of project, 1969 (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Publicity, 1958-1964 (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - Reception - ACLU - Neier, 1978 (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - Research, 1976-1977 (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - Research projects, 1958-1959 (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - Research project, 1959-1960 (Box 37, Folder 13)
  - Self-study, 1957-1966 (Box 37, Folder 14)
    Includes founding papers of Hays Program
- Series VI: Private legal work.
  - Land, Richard, 1985 (Box 37, Folder 15)
  - Laverne v. Corning, 1963-1975 (Box 37, Folder 16)
  - Native American Rights Fund (NARF) - Administration/General, 1978-1993 (Box 37, Folder 17)
  - NARF - Disqualification, 1984-1985 (Box 37, Folder 18)
  - NARF - Intervention, 1984 (Box 37, Folder 19)
  - NARF - Miscellaneous correspondence and memos, 1982 (Box 37, Folder 20)
  - NARF - Post-1790, 1978-1980 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - NARF - Post-1790, 1981-1984 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - NARF - Pre-1790 / File # 1 of 3, 1979-1986 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - NARF - Pre-1790 / File # 2 of 3, 1981 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - NARF - Pre-1790 / File # 3 of 3, 1983-1984 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - NARF - Pre-1790 Case, 1986 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - NARF - Pre-1790 Trial, 1983-1984 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - NARF - Settlements, 1977-1984 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - NARF - Supreme Court, 1983-1989 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - NARF - Supreme Court briefs, 1983 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - NARF - Supreme Court briefs, 1984-1988 (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Rosenthal and Rosenthal - Administrative, 1987-1988 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Rosenthal and Rosenthal - Clean Air Act, 1987-1989 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Rosenthal and Rosenthal - Miscellaneous: Board of Estimate, political action, etc, 1984-1988 (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Rosenthal and Rosenthal - PR (Promotion), 1984-1987 (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Rosenthal and Rosenthal - Supreme Court Certiorari, 1985-1988 (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - Rosenthal and Rosenthal - Various briefs, 1984-1987 (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - Rosenthal and Rosenthal - Various briefs, 1985-1988 (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - Straus Case, 1981-1982 (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - Wilder v. Sugarman - Articles and non-legal memos, 1973-1974 (Box 39, Folder 12)
  - Wilder v. Sugarman - Articles and non-legal memos, 1971-1974 (Box 39, Folder 13)
  - Wilder v. Sugarman - Articles and non-legal memos, 1973-1975 (Box 39, Folder 14)
  - Wilder v. Sugarman - Citizens' Committee for Children, 1974 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Wilder v. Sugarman - Consent decrees, 1973-1974 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Wilder v. Sugarman - Consultants and other jurisdictions, 1974 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Wilder v. Sugarman - Correspondence - Federation of Jewish Philanthropies of New York and non-Wilder legal memo, 1974 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Wilder v. Sugarman - Correspondence - Judge Justine Polier, 1973-1974 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Wilder v. Sugarman - Correspondence and information - Catholic Charities, 1974 (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Wilder v. Sugarman - Correspondence and miscellaneous, 1974-1977 (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Wilder v. Sugarman - Deposition, Feb 1971 (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - Wilder v. Sugarman - Federation of Protestant Welfare Agencies memos and meetings, internal newsletter, 1973-1974 (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Wilder v. Sugarman - Finances, 1973-1974 (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Wilder v. Sugarman - Interrogatories - answers, data, 1969-1973 (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Wilder v. Sugarman - Legal briefs and memos, 1973-1974 (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - Wilder v. Sugarman - Legal memoranda, 1971-1973 (Box 40, Folder 13)
  - Wilder v. Sugarman - Legal memoranda, 1970-1973 (Box 40, Folder 14)
  - Wilder v. Sugarman - Legal memoranda, 1973-1974 (Box 40, Folder 15)
  - Wilder v. Sugarman - Memos and correspondence with Jewish groups, 1973-1974 (Box 40, Folder 16)
  - Wilder v. Sugarman - Miscellaneous, 1973-1977 (Box 40, Folder 17)
  - Wilder v. Sugarman - Miscellaneous legal memos, 1973-1974 (Box 40, Folder 18)
  - Wilder v. Sugarman - Notes, Federation of Protestant Welfare Agencies' position, drafts, 1973-1974 (Box 40, Folder 19)
  - Wilder v. Sugarman - People and agencies in the Federation of Protestant Welfare Agencies, 1973 (Box 40, Folder 20)
  - Wilder v. Sugarman - Settlement proposals., 1974-1976 (Box 40, Folder 21)
  - Wilder v. Sugarman - Social science defenses, 1974 (Box 40, Folder 22)
- Series VII: Audio-visual materials.
  - "NORMAN DORSEN - 'Altering History: The American Civil Liberties Union'" (audiocassette), Undated (Box 41, Folder data_value_missing_3823c2d4af8eec0147b24cccf2e2ebba)
  - "The Investigator" (audiocassette), Undated (Box 41, Folder data_value_missing_ebc8ef92e60198cf370e1752868530d4)
  - "ACLU talk by ND on radio or speech" (audiocassette), Undated (Box 41, Folder data_value_missing_c7d9a6628fe9be677923ff6564212916)
  - Unmarked (audiocassette), Undated (Box 41, Folder data_value_missing_3d279b2de1e05963349be7c77669546a)
  - "Books for the Bar Record #1 2/4/69" (reel-to-reel audiotape), Feb 1969 (Box 41, Folder data_value_missing_66609d10ade5808b4b9f06c7fc3d7f1f)
  - "Books for the Bar Record #2 2/4/69" (reel-to-reel audiotape), Feb 1969 (Box 41, Folder data_value_missing_9c27dd1fc3f38a9768631643281f3bbd)
  - "'Straight Talk' Tuesday Dec 7 1971 Professor of Law NYU Law School ACLU Norman Dorsen Kenneth J. MULLANE DUB" (reel-to-reel audiotape), Dec 1971 (Box 41, Folder data_value_missing_d60a6dc2d1fb6b36f321e9299bea8d58)
  - "STATE YOUR CASE 3/17/86 (ND) Radio talk show" (audiocassette), Mar 1986 (Box 41, Folder data_value_missing_dd5921b9cedd7c3314f65225565a10fb)
  - "87-8 Protection of Civil Liberties. Norman Dorsen" (audiocassette), Aug 1987 (Box 41, Folder data_value_missing_629147640a5c6dfac529eb88649cb624)
  - "Professor Norman Dorsen Harvard Club 5/6/92" (audiocassette), May 1992 (Box 41, Folder data_value_missing_2226313b33464d610107c2de2fa85bdf)
  - "Norman Dorsen - Cornwall Library talk - McCarthy / ND Army-Mc talk Cornwall Library August 1993" (audiocassette), Aug 1993 (Box 41, Folder data_value_missing_fe0a76f585c05eb571f5e956ae8c610b)
  - "NOVEMBER 20, 1998 FRIDAY (COPY) NEW YORK UNIVERSITY SCHOOL OF LAW CONSTITUTIONAL RIGHTS & CHANGING CIVIL SOCIETY: A ROUNDTABLE ON CONSTITUTIONALISM TAPE #1" (audiocassette), Nov 1998 (Box 41, Folder data_value_missing_602db17bdaf2f2544fb6016172d7ea5c)
  - "NOVEMBER 20, 1998 FRIDAY (COPY) NEW YORK UNIVERSITY SCHOOL OF LAW CONSTITUTIONAL RIGHTS & CHANGING CIVIL SOCIETY: A ROUNDTABLE ON CONSTITUTIONALISM TAPE #2" (audiocassette), Nov 1998 (Box 41, Folder data_value_missing_d948a82218b4a2ccebde5ab8d656f81c)
  - "Annual Survey Dedication to Norman Dorsen MARCH 01, 2002, THURSDAY (COPY)" (audiocassette), Mar 2001 (Box 41, Folder data_value_missing_26dc7b8f8dddd766535d4c4e6d7c96b7)
  - "Norman Dorsen Court TV" (VHS), Undated (Box 42, Folder data_value_missing_81796585d5837d9bab98da3218d54a8c)
  - "FIRING LINE DEBATE AT NYU LAW: 'WALL OF SEPARATION… CHURCH AND STATE…" (VHS), Undated (Box 42, Folder data_value_missing_30b1e58a6c9242ec3c89b5821739a23f)
  - "LOOKING AHEAD CIVIL LIBERTIES IN THE FUTURE ACLU Public Education Department (212) 944-9800 TRT 11:20" (VHS), Undated (Box 42, Folder data_value_missing_17af65da9dabf5da64f834d931ce321e)
  - "Point of Order" (VHS), Undated (Box 42, Folder data_value_missing_dccc24937a8b2273387a765c6c60560b)
  - "The Expanding Bill of Rights: The Warren Court and Beyond" (VHS), Undated (Box 42, Folder data_value_missing_fe19b33390b38a3ee0479a187a6f0d1e)
  - "FIRING LINE AT NYU LAW: 'SEPARATION OF CHURCH AND STATE, PARTS I & II'" (VHS), Undated (Box 42, Folder data_value_missing_3e0d8d60a212d0b6f642aed0b75fc1ff)
  - "Norman Dorsen / 1. Straight Talk July 1, 1984 / TODAY July 4, 1984 / From The Editor's Desk July 15, 1984" (BETA), Jul 1984 (Box 42, Folder data_value_missing_618baff5107643965345b6dad9986bad)
  - "ACLU/FEDERALIST DEBATE DONOHUE V. DORSEN 3/8/90 - AMES COURTROOM" (VHS), Mar 1990 (Box 42, Folder data_value_missing_965fd1e66230a59960c41b3bbfe06cd5)
  - "ACLU/FEDERALIST DEBATE DONOHUE V. DORSEN 3/8/90 - AMES COURTROOM" (VHS), Mar 1990 (Box 42, Folder data_value_missing_f2d839c8f495ef533cde4fd394bcdaf3)